Abdi Ahmed

Front End Web Developer

Dedicated and efficient Front End Web developer with 2+ years of hands-on experience in designing and developing user interface. In addition to my employment history, I have developed five different projects, including my Portfolio website, all from scratch, to demonstrate the wide range of my skills. Some of the technologies used in these projects are Firebase, Angular, JavaScript/TypeScript, Bootstrap, CSS3/SASS and HTML5. I also have some experience in the backend like NodeJS/Express, NoSQI and SQL databases.

Contact

Address

Powell, OH 43065

Phone

(614) 210-3388

E-mail

aa86@outlook.com

Portfolio

https://abdionline.com

LinkedIn

linkedin.com/in/abdisamed

Skills

Responsive Design

JavaScript /TypeScript

Angular

Bootstrap

HTML 5

CSS 3

SASS

Work History

2015-02 - Front End Web Developer

2015-10 Kaah IT Solution, Pretoria

- Landing page design,
- Test and Debug

E-Commerce Web App

- Retrieves products from Firebase/Firestore,
- Allow User to Add items to cart (LocalStorage),
 Delete, change quantity, and Calculate the Total,
- ♦ Sign-Up and Sign-In functionality

Weather App

- Utilizes the OpenWeatherMap API,
- Request user's location,
- Displays the current & the next 5 days forecast

Quiz App

- ♦ Ten randomized questions with four possible answers,
- Must select an answer to move on to the next,
- Answers will be highlighted with specific color

Hotel (Cloned)

A landing page for a hotel.

Education

2012-02 - B.S. in Computer Science (EQ)

2016-11 *UNISA* - Pretoria, SA